瞧瞧你 打扮得像个女孩 为何改变
Look at you, dressed like a girl. Why the change?
旱冰队又想招你去了吗
Did the roller-derby team try to recruit you again?
没有 我要跟本约会
No. I have a date with Ben.
感觉你看起来不是很乐意啊
You don't seem too excited about it.
他人是很好啦 而且...
Well, I mean, he's really nice, and --
懂 你觉得无聊了 我也是
Got it. You're bored, and so am I.
分手吧
Break up.
我就想看看外边还有何种男人
I mean, I just want to see what else is out there.
-我这样有错吗 -天啊
- Does that make me a bad person? - Oh, my God.
我们还在讨论这个事情吗
Are we still talking about this?
我已经解决你的问题了 就今天
I solved your problem. Today.
找一家热闹的餐厅 免得他大吵大闹
Crowded restaurant so he doesn't make a scene.
深呼吸 然后直接跟他说了
Just deep breath and say it.
天大好消息 有人拿厕纸炸了我们家
Fantastic news! Someone TP'd our house!
万圣节狂欢正在逼近
Halloween fun is afoot.
老爸 我真心想为你感到兴奋
Dad, I really want to be excited for you,
可这是万圣节
but Halloween?
我们都已经老到可以投票了
We're almost old enough to vote.
吓到我了
Got me!
值得吗
Worth it?
怎么 你长大就不能让你害怕一下了吗
Oh, what, you're too old for a little scare?
最令人害怕的是你离当外婆可能只隔了
The scariest thing is you could be a cheap pick-up line,
一次搭讪 两瓶啤酒和九个月时间
two beers, and nine months away from being a grandparent,
而你却冒着窒息的风险躲在冰箱里
and you just risked asphyxiation in the fridge.
我们又不是带你们去敲门要糖果
It's not like we're taking you trick-or-treating.
成年人也有成年人过万圣节的方式啊
There are grown-up ways to enjoy Halloween.
南瓜船比赛怎么样
How about pumpkin-boat racing?
小卡以前在密苏里州常做
Cam used to do it in Missouri.
找一个巨大的南瓜
Take a giant pumpkin,
去顶
cut the top off,
去瓤 坐进 开划
gut it, hop in, sail away.
来吧
Let's do it.
我爱死这个创意
I'm so married to this idea,
爱它到我跟人说笑话 它会像老婆一样翻白眼
it rolls its eyes when I make jokes in public.
学着点 也许能对你甩掉本带来帮助
Take notes -- This might help you out with Ben later.
老妈 老爸
Mom, Dad?
你们与万圣节
You and Halloween have had
曾一起度过无数欢乐时光
some great times together.
但如今物是人非
But it's over.
你们对过节来说太老了 令人不忍直视
You're way too old, and it's hard to look at.
跟你的事真的能串起来呢
Wow, it really lines up.
我知道怎么回事了
I see what's going on here.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
我还没有说
I haven't communicated how big
这南瓜会有多大
this pumpkin's gonna be.
听过童书《超级红卜卜》那只两层楼高的狗吗
You guys know Clifford -- the Big Red Dog?
我们不想玩
We're not doing this.
而且 我们都有约会了
Plus, we all have dates.
-但是 -我觉得他们过那年纪了
- But-- -I think they're past it.
有点太残酷了 对吧
That was kinda harsh, huh?
亲爱的 你别太往心里去
Oh, honey, don't take it too personally.
我吗 明显是针对你的啊 冰箱怪物
Me? That was directed at you, fridge monster.
你才是痴迷过万圣节的人啊
You're the one who's obsessed with Halloween.
亲爱的 是你建议
Honey, you were the one who suggested
找一个巨大的南瓜
getting a giant pumpkin
然后让我们坐在里面划船
and having us sail away in it
像是动画里的老鼠一家
like a family of cartoon mice.
所有南瓜对老鼠来说都是巨大的
All pumpkins are giant to mice.
我们俩争谁更迷恋一个
There is no use in us arguing over who's more obsessed
已经离我们远去的节日毫无意义
with a holiday that's behind us already.
离我们可远了
Way behind us.
好了 我得走了 亲爱的
All right. I got to get going, honey.
对 今天过得开心哦
Yeah, have a good one.
-很好 拜拜 -拜
- Great. Buh-bye. - Mm-hmm, bye.
计划有变 各位
Change of plans, fellas.
快上车
Hop in the car.
哎哟哟
Well, well, well.
你们城里人
You city folk
起得可真晚啊
sure are late risers.
我猜你们的公鸡有个稍候再叫的按钮
I guess your rooster has a snooze button.
你每天都说一模一样的话好搞笑哦
It's funny how you say the exact, same thing every morning.
由于我们的包工头暂停维修我们的厨房
Since our contractor took a break from rehabbing kitchens
-改成"修"身养性去戒赌 -对
- to rehab a gambling problem... - Yeah.
杰就接手了 我们就开始住在这儿
...Jay took over, and we've been staying here.
老爸花了不少时间精力
It's been a lot of Dad,
但是... 继续住在家里
but it -- it just became too impractical
变得太不方便了
to continue living at home.
我们需要再涂一层亮光漆
We're gonna use another coat of varnish.
味道应该不会太重
The fumes shouldn't be too noticeable.
-好 -天啊 莉莉
- Okay. - Okay. Oh, boy. Lily.
天啊 她被熏倒了
Oh, gosh! Okay, she's down!
我们住在没有厨房的地方很不容易
It's been hard on us, living without a kitchen.
厨房烧了已经过了六周
It's been, uh, six weeks now since it burned down.
从你把厨房烧了
Since you burned it down.
从我把厨房烧了
Since I burned it down.
还蓄意让我以为是我干的
And then maliciously made me think I did it
然后利用我的自责谋取你的私利
and leveraged my guilt for your own selfish gain.
还蓄意让你以为
Then maliciously made you think
是你干的 然后利用...
that you did it, and leveraged --
亲爱的 你不要再自责了
Honey, you got to stop beating yourself up.
好吧
Okay.
我要给乔做燕麦粥
I was going to make Joe's oatmeal.
你真的有必要把五个炉子都占着吗
Do you really have to use all five burners?
这道菜就叫
Well, it is called
五个炉子肉馅饼
Five Burner Meat Pie,
是我们那里的万圣佳节传统菜肴
and it's the traditional dish back at the Halloween festival,
让我感觉像在老家过节
so it kinda makes me feel like I'm there.
燕麦粥还没好吗
No oatmeal?
我不等了 把胡子戴上吧
Guess I could put my beard on now.
快来
Come over here!
有点疼 对不起 但是我崇拜的上帝
Look, I'm sorry, but the God I worship
是不会露出他自己的发根的 所以...
does not let his roots show, so...
两周前
Two weeks ago,
我们邀请米奇和小卡来这边住
we invited Mitch and Cam to stay here.
是你邀请的
You invited them.
对我们来说绝非易事
It's been hard on us,
但我们哥伦比亚人的传统
but it's part of our Colombian heritage...
是你的传统
Your heritage.
就是欢迎家人
...to welcome family
绝对不赶他们出去
and to never kick them out,
即便有时候他们也许有一些越界行为
even when they might have some boundary issues.
我回工地了
I'm heading back to the job site.
我打算让伙计们休息一会儿
Gonna let the guys knock off
请他们喝点儿小酒
for a little liqu-or-treating.
团队就应该这样...
Well, that is how you manage...
才能把活拖到圣诞节才干完
...to stretch a job until Christmas.
好了 你现在过去
Okay, you need to go over there,
问问他还要修多久
find out how long this is gonna take.
我想把我的厨房要回来
I want my kitchen back.
好吧 老爸
Okay, uh, Dad?
我们很感激你的辛勤工作
W-We appreciate all your hard work,
但是我们的进度好像有点落后了
but we're running a little past schedule.
活总得干完才算完啊
The job is done when the job is done.
你们想要快的话
You want it faster,
下次烧个书架好了
next time, burn down a bookshelf.
很明显他根本就不会弄
Well, clearly, he doesn't know what he's doing
而且骄傲得不肯承认
and he's too proud to admit it.
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
我的早餐就是一根女人能量棒吗
My breakfast is a LUNA Bar for women.
想点办法啊
Do something.
他们是家人啊 你想要我怎么办
They're family. What do you want me to do?
你得开了你父亲
You need to fire your father.
别担心 我会处理的
Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
-米奇尔 -我对天发誓
- Mitchell. - I swear to God.
答应我 你会把他们赶走
Promise me you'll get rid of them.
好
Okay.
要让我相信你
Make me believe it.
我对你发誓
I swear to you.
我不是跟男人约会
I didn't have a date with a guy,
而是跟德丝蒂尼[命运]约会了
but rather a date with Destiny.
德丝蒂尼是我参加的视镜的
Destiny was the name of the casting director
选角导演
I was auditioning for.
我看到一则招聘邮轮和声歌手广告
I saw an ad for backup singers on a cruise ship,
我立刻知道是缘分来了
and I knew it was fate.
我有天籁般的嗓音 又喜欢唱K
I have a killer voice, I love karaoke,
更擅长在船上派对
and I'm great at partying on boats.
海莉·邓菲
Haley Dunphy?
啊嘿[船员用词]
Ahoy!
我会说"船语"哦
I speak "Ship."
一路顺风哦 船友们
Bon voyage, mateys.
技惊四座
I crushed it.
连我的谦逊都是秒杀全场
I even crushed the modesty after.
"不 谢谢你们给我这次演唱机会"
"No, thank you for the chance to sing."
贝丝和杰西卡
Beth and Jessica...
-拜拜 -你俩留下
- Bye. - ...you guys stay.
海莉 我们再联系吧
Haley, we'll be in touch.
知道你俩是
I had a good feeling about you two
卡帕姐妹会的之后 我就很看好你们
when I found out you were fellow Kappa sisters.
等下
Wait.
你们是一个姐妹会的吗
You're all in the same sorority?
是最棒的姐妹会
Only the best sorority.
卡帕 卡帕 塞塔
Kappa Kappa Theta!
-我想要... -行了行了
- Ooh, I wanna take ya - Okay, okay.
这就是大家都讨厌大学生的原因
This is why everyone hates college graduates.
我会走的
I will walk out that door,
但至少给我一点尊重
but at least show me enough respect to admit
承认这个决定根本和才华无关
that this decision had nothing to do with talent.
因为众所周知 我是最棒的
Because everyone knows that I was the best.
挺有勇气
Well, that took a lot of guts.
跟我来
Come with me.
再来看一遍你的试唱吧
Let's take a second look at your audition.
♪ 拥抱我 指责我 ♪
♪ To hold me, to scold me ♪
♪ 因为我不乖时 我真的很不乖 ♪
'♪ Cause when I'm bad, I'm so, so bad ♪
看吧 我超棒的
See? I'm fantastic.
接着看
Mm. Keep watching.
♪ 让我们来跳最后一支舞 ♪
♪ So let's dance, the last dance ♪
♪ Let's dance, the last dance ♪
好了 我看够了
Okay. I've seen enough.
不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no.
我得忍着看完这一整段
I had to sit through this whole thing.
你也别想跑
You will, too.
你们要知道 这是60年代的
You got to remember, this was the '60s.
那时柜橱生意的竞争十分激烈
Competition in the closet game was fierce,
人们都在追逐下一个大存储的点子
everybody chasing after the next big storage idea.
历史学家称这段时期为空间战[太空竞赛]
Historians remember this period as the "Space race."
-米奇尔 -爸
- Oh, Mitchell. - Uh, Dad?
我想看下厨房
Uh, I would like to see the kitchen.
我倒想喝啤酒能让我的头发再生
I'd like to think that drinking beer makes my hair grow back,
但生活就是不公平的
but life ain't fair.
好吧 我们得谈谈
Okay, uh, then w-we need to talk.
你们先出去下
You guys want to take it outside?
我得跟小赫哥谈一下
I need a couple minutes with El Rojo.
赫就是"红色"
Rojo means "Red."
好吧
Yeah.
我组装东西很快 不像你的工人
I put things together quickly, unlike your workers,
这也是我来这里的原因
which is, uh, why I'm here.
爸 如果这活对你来说太难了...
Um, Dad, if this is too much for you --
等一下
Now, wait a second.
你不会是来炒我鱿鱼的吧
You're not here to fire me, are you?
什么 不是啦
What? No.
呵 那词太重了
Pfft! That's a strong word.
我这一生经历过太多炒鱿鱼
I've done enough axing in my time
我知道你这个表情
to recognize the look.
干脆点吧
Just do it.
我 我本来更希望
See, now, I was -- I was hoping
这更像是一场对话
this would be more of a conversation.
你跟人对质的功力一直很差
Never been much for confrontation.
你要是有本事打开天窗说亮话
You weren't engaged to a woman six months in law school
也不会上法学院时 跟一个女的订婚半年了
because you were good at dropping the hammer.
你们不是还一起养了猫吗
Didn't you guys get a cat together?
好了 没错
Okay, you know? Y-Y-Yes!
你被炒了 行了吧
You're fired! Okay?
你就是个没能力的戏精
You're an incompetent man-diva.
你唯一建过的一样东西
The only thing you've ever built
就是橱柜 也就是个装空气的盒子
is a closet -- I.E. a box of air.
你走吧
So get out,
小心你的大屁股
and don't let the door hit you
别被门夹了
on your ample behind.
不错
Nicely done.
不过对橱柜的攻击有些没必要
Maybe an unnecessary shot at closets,
毕竟你没出"柜"整整22年
particularly from someone who was in one for 22 years,
但
but...
我明白了
Yeah, I get it.
我去拿我的东西
I'll just grab my stuff.
天啊 爸 你弄完了
Oh, my God. Dad, it's -- it's done!
-对 -那你怎么不说呢
- Yep. - Well, why didn't you say something?
我看到你怒气冲冲走进来
Well, I saw you marching in here,
感觉要发飙
loaded for bear.
而你很少对别人发飙
You don't usually go off on people,
我觉得让你发泄一下也好
so I thought it'd be good for you.
-感觉如何 -我不喜欢那种感觉
- How'd it feel? - I didn't love it.
但这个厨房真是太赞了
But this kitchen is amazing.
我还剩一件事要做
I only got one more thing to do.
我得把玻璃装进门中 然后安装好门
I've got to seal glass in the door and hang it.
你想要那个彩色玻璃
Now, you want to go with the stain
还是小卡选的透明玻璃
or the clear pane Cam picked?
你知道吗 我是在跳蚤市场上买的这个
Hmm. You know what? I-I bought this at a flea market.
他们不知道是从哪来的
They're not sure of the origin.
可能来自毁于地震的
It either came from a 17th-century Flemish cathedral
17世纪弗兰芒教堂
that collapsed in an earthquake
也可能是中学生演音乐剧《修女》时的道具
or a high-school production of "Nunsense."
我真心喜欢这个
Oh, I do love this.
我是不是该问问小卡的意见
Should -- Should I ask Cam if it's okay?
你差点炒了你爸
You almost just fired your dad.
该不会在这事上犯怂吧
You're not gonna go shy on me on this --
你说得对
You know what? You're right.
就要这个了
It's this glass.
这就对了嘛
That's it. Hey?
你想不想帮我完成这个
You want to help me finish this off,
就咱俩
just the two of us?
你知道吗
You know what?
好的 我愿意
Yes. Yeah, I-I would.
让我系上这个
Let me just strap on this bad boy.
所有的工具都在地上摆好了
So, all the tools have been laid out.
接下来呢
What next?
-菲尔 -卡罗尔
- Phil. - Hey, Carol.
我刚知道我家小孩把你院子弄成这样
I just found out my kids did this to your yard,
实在很抱歉
and we are so sorry.
不用啦 万圣节嘛
Don't be. It's Halloween.
每年四大恶作剧日子之一
It's one of the four biggest prank days of the year.
万圣节 愚人节
It's this, April Fools' Day,
愚人节前一天
and the day before April Fools' Day,
因为没人会有防备
'cause no one sees it coming.
第四个呢
What's the fourth?
想得美 卡罗尔
Nice try, Carol.
重点是
The point is,
有一天你醒来
you're gonna wake up one morning
发现你家小孩不再恶作剧了
and find out that your kids don't TP anymore.
珍惜可爱的小坏蛋还作恶的日子吧
Cherish these days with your adorable little vandals.
感谢你的理解
Well, I appreciate the understanding,
但我想给他们点教训
but I'm trying to teach them a lesson.
我会给他们教训的
Oh, I'm gonna teach them a lesson,
因为报仇的时候到啦
'cause it's payback time.
恶作剧大战正式开始
Pranks wars have begun.
太棒了
Yes!
好了 孩子们
Okay, kids.
我想邓菲先生还有更重要的事要做
I think Mr. Dunphy has better things to do
才不会浪费时间和你们恶作剧大战
than spend his day in a prank war with you.
好消息 孩子们 我没事
Good news, boys. I don't.
好吧
Okay.
你完成不了作业
We cannot take you trick-or-treating
就不带你去讨糖
if you don't finish your homework.
你俩不是有话要说嘛
Didn't you two have something you wanted to talk about?
小卡
Um, so, Cam...
我正在试着连无线网
I'm trying to get Wi-Fi
这样才能看我老家的
so I can watch the pumpkin weigh-in
万圣节南瓜称重赛
at the Halloween festival back home.
25年前
You know, 25 years ago,
我培育了威奇托最大的南瓜
I raised the largest Wichita Thumper,
至今此记录还没被打破
and the record still stands.
多多包涵
I am so sorry.
这话怎么说都听起来像小卡卖瓜
There's no way to say that that doesn't sound braggy.
不不 你这么说还好啦
No, no, you just did fine.
但我想和你说
Um, but I just wanted to say to you --
每个南瓜 都有一个故事
You know, as with every pumpkin, there's a story.
那是一个寒冷的夜晚
It was a cold, bitter night,
窗户传来咚咚咚敲打的声音
when tap-tap-tap on the window.
惊奇的是居然是我南瓜的藤
Darn if it wasn't the vine of my pumpkin,
在外面摇晃
just out there trembling away.
真是个好故事
That is a great story.
然后 我爸就把南瓜
Next thing I know, Daddy's pulling the pumpkin
拉进了窗户 当然很小心 没弄断藤
through the window, careful, of course, not to break the vine.
之后几个月 它成为我家的一员
And for months, it just became a part of our household --
大家跨过它才能进厨房
people stepping over it to get into the kitchen,
它挡住了半个电视
blocked half the TV.
我们以为《脱线家族》
We thought "The Brady Bunch"
讲的是3个可爱女孩子的故事
was just about three lovely girls.
但没人抱怨
Oh, but nobody complained.
当然 我获得了总冠军
Sure, I won Grand Champion,
还得到下一个龙卷风的命名权
you know, and the right to name the next tornado.
但我印象最深的
But the thing I remember most
是我家人为我所做的牺牲
are the sacrifices my family made for just me.
这就是我家乡对待家人的方式
That's how we do family where I'm from.
我老家那也是这么对待家人的
That's how we do family where I am from!
歌洛莉亚 我得赶紧连上网
Oh, Gloria! I got to get this Wi-Fi.
你都看见了 是不是
You saw that, didn't you?
人在做天在看
I see everything.
你们十分钟后突袭办公室
In 10 minutes, you're gonna storm the office,
在所有人慌乱的时候
everybody freaks out,
我神奇女侠现身 击败丧尸
I go Wonder Woman, fight off the zombies.
-明白了 -好
- Got it. - Okay.
我的孩子们或许不感兴趣了
My kids may be over it,
但办公室的大家喜欢万圣节克莱尔
but at the office, they love Halloween Claire.
这是在普里契特衣柜工作的好处之一
It's one of the perks of working at Pritchett's Closets.
虽然接下来一年你都得帮忙付咖啡钱
Sure, you got to pitch in for coffee the rest of the year,
但万圣节那天的大戏是免费的
but on October 31st, the show is free.
-大家马上就来开会了 -很好
- Everyone's on their way here to a meeting. - Great.
今年不搞角色扮演了吗
Oh, so, no costume this year?
应该不会
Apparently not.
明智之举
Oh, good call.
所有人都受不了
Everyone was so sick of it.
变装压力太大了
The pressure to dress up!
他们求我来和你谈谈来着
You know, they begged me to talk to you,
但我说 "不 克莱尔会意识到
but I said, "No, Claire will realize
大家有多不情愿的"
how miserable everybody is."
-这么说谁都 -我想喝你的...
- So no-nobody -- - I vant to drink your --
我们不用再搞角色扮演了
We don't have to do it anymore.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God!
你知道我今早照镜子时哭了吗
You know, I cried in the mirror this morning?
大伙 大伙 都结束了
Guys, everybody. It's over.
终于不用再搞这一套了 别担心
The whole thing's finally over. No worries.
是啊
Yeah.
我先失陪片刻
I'm just gonna need a quick second.
不不不 别别别
No, no, no. Stop, stop, stop, stop.
-抱歉 -快走
- Sorry. - Go.
请各位
So, if you could just,
注意看屏幕
uh, take your attention to the screen, please.
市场调查表明...
And... for the market research --
拜托 没人想来这一出
Please. Nobody wants this.
她想给我们个惊喜
Oh, she's surprising us.
丧尸来袭了
It's a zombie attack.
万岁
Yay.
但神奇女侠来救我们了 太好了
Oh, but it's Wonder Woman to the rescue, yeah.
神奇女侠 救救我
Wonder Woman, help me.
好吧 好戏结束了
Okay, fun's over.
快点 都走吧
Come on. Everybody --
好吧 好吧
Okay! All right!
给你 拿走 拿走
Here! Take it! Take it!
天啊 我太抱歉了
Ow, God! I am so sorry!
你这么早就回来了
You're home early.
我本来与俱乐部一个叫艾比的女生打得火热
I was into this awesome girl, Abby, from the club.
我们本打算今晚进入下一个阶段
And tonight, we were gonna take things to the next level,
也就是 你懂 性
which is, you know, sex.
想个代号总是好的
Always classy to name it.
但问题是她特别善妒
But the one problem is she's super jealous
她貌似觉得我在和
and got this idea I was messing around
小卖部的卡拉胡搞
with Carla from the snack bar.
我的确有
Which I was.
所以我得在去见艾比前
So I had to break it off with Carla
和卡拉分手
before seeing Abby.
顺利吗
How'd it go?
她用食品夹把我一顿抽
I got a major tong lashing.
搞什么
What the heck?
卡拉 冷静点 等一下
Carla, calm down! Wait -- Oh!
等等 让我解释
Wait, wait, I can explain!
让我解释 谁来救救我
I can explain! Somebody help!
于是我遮住我的淤伤
So I covered up my bruises
清理了所有和小卖部有关的证据
and checked for any snack-bar-related evidence
才去见艾比
before seeing Abby.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
我传你的照片时扭伤了脖子
I got whiplash passing a picture of you.
事情进展得不能更顺利了
Things couldn't have been going any better...
我爸肯定会讨厌死你
My dad is going to hate you.
然后变得更顺利了
...and then they got better.
直到...
Until...
芥末
Mustard?
你分明讨厌芥末
You hate mustard.
你个王八蛋 你又去和卡拉胡搞了
You son of a bitch! You were with Carla!
我知道有完美金句
I knew there was one perfect thing
说出来就能挽救大局
I could say to save it.
宝贝 她不过是小卖部零食
Baby, I just snack with her.
你才是主菜
You're the main course.
我真的只是引用别人的话
I did not come up with that thing.
好了
All right.
看起来不错
Looks good.
这是我帮忙装好的
You know, I helped build that.
我感觉像个真的建筑工人呢
I-I feel like a real construction guy.
我有点希望此时能路过个女人
I kinda wish a woman would walk by
好让我说点物化女性的话
so I could objectify her.
那最爽了
It's the best.
我们刚刚完成了一项工程
Listen, we just finished the project.
来 和你老爹去逛一圈庆祝胜利
Now, come on. Take a victory lap with your old man.
乐意奉陪
I'd love to.
我倒要看看小卡
Hey, and I defy Cam to find
能挑出这玻璃什么毛病来
anything wrong with that window.
它真的为你的厨房添色不少
It really gives your kitchen some flair.
歌洛莉亚
Oh, hey, Gloria.
我终于找到无线网信号最好的地方了
I finally found a great spot for the Wi-Fi
正好赶上南瓜称重
just in time for the pumpkin weigh-in.
我泡澡时你居然坐在这
You sit here while I take a bath?!
你忘了我是基吗
I'm gay? Hello?
我对你这件华美的浴袍更感兴趣
I'm more fixated on that fabulous robe.
我下次泡澡时绝对要借来穿
I am so borrowing that for my next bath.
你洗澡水还没放掉吧
You didn't drain the water yet, did you?
好吧 够了
Okay, that's it!
我再也受不了你了
I can't handle you anymore!
你占据我的厨房
You take over my kitchen!
我一转身 你就蹬鼻子上脸
I turn around, and you're in my face!
连体婴都比我有更多个人空间
Siamese twins have more privacy than me!
从我家滚出去 再也别回来了
Get out of my house, and never come back!
厨房装修好了
Well, the kitchen's done.
看来我能搬回家去了
So I guess I can move back home.
他就不能早一分钟发这条信息吗
He couldn't have sent you that message one minute ago?
没关系的 歌洛莉亚
It's okay, Gloria.
我知道你的真实想法比较好
It's better that I know how you actually feel.
南瓜节的主席台上
Well, there seems to be a lot of hubbub
似乎有不小的骚动
on the dais at pump' fest.
他们为什么要聚集还在世的历任市长
Why are they gathering all the living mayors?
正式宣布
It's official.
达拉·宝华特女士打破了旧南瓜记录
Ms. Darla Bowater has shattered the old pumpkin record.
好吧
Okay.
我想你能理解 发生这些事
I'm sure you'll understand, under these circumstances,
我会快速收拾东西 泡个澡
I'll just quickly gather my things, take that bath,
然后... 走人
and... be on my way.
是哪位
Who is it?
联合快递特快邮件
Special delivery from UPS.
联合恶作剧快递
United Prank Service.
这个恶作剧我参考了历史书
I went to the history books for this one,
追溯到恶作剧鼻祖
all the way back to the first practical joke --
特洛伊木马
the Trojan Horse.
不过我用喷彩代替了大刀
Only I swapped out silly string for broad swords
用欢笑代替了谋杀
and laughter for murder.
好的
Okay.
你们喜欢恶作剧是吧
You guys want to prank?
那就来恶作剧
Let's prank.
不
Oh, no.
Oh, no!
不
No!
Nooooo!
不 老天爷啊
No! God!
他们不过是朝你院子里扔了点厕纸
They just put some toilet paper in your yard.
他为什么要这么对我们 妈妈
Why would he do this to us, Mother?
这是场意外
It was an accident!
毛毛哪去了 我找不到毛毛了
Where's Fluffy?! I can't find Fluffy!
别担心 我帮你找
Don't worry! I'll help you find her!
我的眼睛
My eye!
快进屋去 快进屋去
Go in the house! Go in the house!
我为什么觉得这么有活力
Oh, why do I feel so energized?
因为满足了建造这份原始男性本能
Because you honored your primal male instinct to build.
-是啊 -曾经贫瘠的荒原
- Yeah. - Where once lay barren fields,
因为像我们这样的男人
because of men like us,
如今成了灯火辉煌的都市
now gleaming cities stand.
都市又是什么 不过是...
And what is a city, but --
装载人类文明的衣柜
A closet for civilization.
这是我这辈子最为你骄傲的一刻
This is the proudest damn moment of my life.
那让我想起了痛苦的回忆
That brings back painful memories.
好像拐到我们家那条街去了
Huh, seems to be turning down our street.
谁能想到啊
Well, what do you know?
中间这块水晶像放大镜一样聚光了
This crystal in the middle acted like a magnifying glass.
-普里契特先生 -嗯
- Mr. Pritchett... - Yeah.
过去两个月内已经发生了两次
...this is the second time in two months.
很开心你这么喜欢我们
We love that you're a fan,
但或许你买本消防员日历就好了
but maybe you should just buy a calendar.
抱歉 米奇 我也很难过
I'm sorry, Mitch. I feel really bad.
你觉得能不能由你来告诉小卡
Do you think maybe you could tell Cam?
我已经不在这儿打工了
Oh, I don't work here anymore.
菲尔 亲爱的
Phil? Honey?
克莱尔
Claire.
没有瞒下去的道理了
There's no sense in hiding it.
我确实买了个巨型南瓜
I did buy a giant pumpkin.
我猜到了
I puzzled that one out.
你说得对
You're right.
我就是个痴迷万圣节的大孩子
I'm a Halloween-obsessed child-man.
你想好过一点吗
Do you want to feel better?
我把丧尸带去公司了 好吗
I took zombies to work, okay?
这馊主意死得好惨
And it died so hard.
真要命 被玛格丽特同情
Oh, my God, to be pitied by Margaret...
我想孩子们是对的
I guess the kids are right.
我们是时候有个成年人的样子了
It's time for us to start acting like adults.
我们可以办晚宴 看舞台剧 开个人退休帐户
We can have dinner parties, see plays, open IRAs.
我们有个人退休账户的吧
We have IRAs, right?
当头棒喝啊 克莱尔
Rude awakening, Claire.
你以为自己是有趣有爱的爸爸
You think you're the fun-loving dad,
给人带来快乐 让童真不死
putting smiles on faces, keeping childhood alive.
结果你只是一个坐在南瓜坦克里
Turns out you're just the weird guy
冲下人家车道的怪叔叔
barreling down a driveway in a pumpkin-tank.
菲尔 我命令你不许再说这种话
Phil, I command you to stop speaking like that.
请你让我沉浸在悲伤中一会行吗
Please let me have my feelings for one second.
不 快转过来 真的 画面很美
No, come on, turn around. Seriously. It's good.
神奇女侠吗
Wonder Woman?
正是 而且我为你做了计划
Yes! And I have plans for you!
谁管其他人怎么想啊
Who cares what anybody thinks?
孩子们吃屎吧 公司的人都吃屎吧
Screw the kids. Screw everybody at work.
万圣节等我们哪天想放弃了才放弃
We'll give up Halloween when we are good and ready.
你们扮的是谁
Who are you guys supposed to be?
你们爸妈也想成为的牛人
Who your parents wish they were.
和本分手进行得并不顺利
Ending things with Ben did not go well.
他一直在帮忙我起头
He kept giving me openings,
但我就是狠不下心说出口
and I just couldn't pull the trigger.
我干嘛一直吃这块不新鲜的面包啊
Why do I keep eating this stale bread?
你也会这样吗
Do you ever do that?
明知有样东西不好
Like, you know something's bad,
但你还是要个不停
but you just keep going in for more
因为这是你面前唯一的选择
'cause it's the only thing in front of you?
对了 有件事挺恶心的
Uh, hey, this is gonna sound really gross,
我手上贴了张止血贴
but I have a Band-Aid on my hand,
在手毛特别浓密的地方 我知道一定会很痛
it's on a super-hairy spot, and I know it's gonna sting.
你能不能帮我撕下来 拜托啦
Would you take it off for me, please?
撕快一点 如果我注定会痛
And do it fast. If I'm gonna be hurt,
那长痛不如短痛
I just want to get it over with.
我想分手
I want to break up.
可以点菜了吗
Ready to order?
你刚才有没有听见我说的话
Uh, did you not just hear what I said?
-没有 什么 -我想分手
- No. What? - I want to break up.
我想点玉米片 你呢
So, I'm thinking nachos. What about you?
-我的天 我在和你分手 -什么
- Oh, my God! I'm breaking up with you! - What?
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
这段时间很开心 但现在都结束了
It's been really great, but now it's over.
求你不要一哭二闹
Please don't make a scene.
我很难过 但我理解
I mean, I'm sad, but I get it.
我们正处于人生不同的阶段
We're in different phases of our lives,
你现在住在离我一小时以外的地方
and you live an hour away from me now,
我上周末也和我前女友
and I made out with my ex
在衣橱大会上亲热了
last weekend at the closet convention,
所以我又有多忠贞呢
so how committed am I?
加上你和我妈咪之间的矛盾
Plus that tension between you and Muh-ma -- Oy.
你背着我偷吃了
You cheated on me?!
我们当时喝醉了 好吗
We were drunk, okay?
而且她很难过
And she was really upset
因为她得把孩子送去大学
'cause she had to drop her daughter off at college.
你个渣男
You suck!
我竟然浪费了那么多时间
To think I wasted so much time
在你这个爱哭粘人幼稚烂人身上
on such a weepy, clingy, Pez-eating snore!
真不敢相信我曾乖乖坐在那儿扮芭比
I can't believe I sat there and pretended to be a doll
让你梳我的头发
as you brushed my hair!
你几乎是我交过最差劲的男朋友了
You are almost the worst boyfriend I have ever had!
最尴尬的一天奖得主是艾丽克丝
Okay, Alex wins most embarrassing day.
先别急着颁奖
Not so fast.
瞧这俩傻子
Look at these two ding dongs.
那是爸妈在一个巨型南瓜里吗
Is that Mom and Dad in a giant "punkin"?
至少这次我们没被拉去
Well, at least we didn't get dragged into it this time.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
对 因为我们另有计划
Yep. Because we got stuff goin' on.
小卡
Cam...
我刚刚其实可以
I'm sure that there were better ways
表达得更好一些
for me to say what I said.
你在打包我的面霜
You're packing my face creams.
不用道歉
No need to apologize.
我知道我踩过界了
I know I crossed boundaries.
我从小的环境就这样
It's how I grew up.
所有人之间都没有秘密
Nobody had secrets from anybody.
高中派对时 "真心话大冒险"我们只玩大冒险
At high-school parties, we just played Dare.
我懂这种感觉
I know the feeling.
我也是在一个小镇上长大的
I grew up in a small town myself.
我们还不得不带陌生人到镇上
We had to bring in a stranger
好让孩子们学会不能和谁说话
so that the children could learn who not to talk to.
我必须说 你的家乡往事
You know, I have to say, sometimes your hometown stories
有时听起来是编的
sound a little made-up.
我很抱歉我说了那些恶毒话
I am sorry that I was mean,
我也很抱歉你不再拥有最大的南瓜了
and I am sorry that you don't have the biggest pumpkin anymore.
其实这已经和保持记录无关了
It's not even about having the record anymore.
那记录是我让小镇生活留在心中的方式
I-It's just how I kept the small town alive in me.
-或许很蠢吧 -才不是
- Probably dumb. - No.
离开自己热爱的地方 是很艰难的事
It's hard when you have to leave a place you love.
每一年 那地方好像都在渐渐消失
Every year, it feels like more of it fades away.
我会很难过 因为我知道
I get very sad because I know
我的口音几乎完全消失了
that my accent is almost completely gone.
总之 我该走了
Anyway, I-I should go.
等等 我有东西给你
Wait. I have something for you.
一颗南瓜籽
A pumpkin seed?
我想或许明年它也能打破记录
I think it can be next year's record-breaker.
天啊 歌洛莉亚
Oh, my... Gloria...
好了
Okay!
-好啦 好啦 -天啊
- All right, all right! - Oh, my gosh!
老天啊
Oh, my God!
我们乘着蔬菜浮在水面上了
We're floating in a vegetable!
乘着巨型蔬菜
In a giant vegetable!
当家人年纪渐长 你有两个选择
As families get older, you have two options --
你可以强迫大家在一起
you can force everyone together,
也可以接受传统会消失
or you can accept that traditions die
人会往前迈进
and people move on.
除非你刚好有个巨型南瓜
Unless you happen to have a giant pumpkin.
你们来这儿干什么呢
Hey! What are you guys doing here?
我们收到暗示了
We got the hint.
我们也来玩 你们才会开心
It wasn't gonna be fun unless we were here, too,
所以我们追踪了你们的手机
so we tracked your phones.
小卡说
Cam says the record
北美45米南瓜赛艇的记录是18秒
for the North American 50-yard pumpkin dash is 18 seconds.
-我们应该能做到 -我们肯定能做到
- I think we can do it! - Oh, I know we can do it!
-给我们计时 -开划
- Time us! - Let's do it!
-好的 -好咧
- Okay! - Okay!
你们能做到 打破18秒记录
You can do it! Beat that 18 seconds!
你们快到了
You're so close!
等等 划到那边去
Wait! There -- row it there!
我们成功了吗 花了18秒吗
Okay. Did we do it? Was that 18 seconds?
是5分钟
5 minutes.
好接近呀
Still close!
事情的始末是这样的
All right, here's what happened.
就在你刚发完短信说厨房弄好后
Right after you sent the text saying the kitchen was done,
检查员忽然上门突击检查
the inspector popped in for a little surprise visit.
现在厨房的装修不合规
Now, it's before violations.
我们得迟几周才能完工
Which pushes us back for a couple of weeks now.
说是我的错 我可以承受小卡的怒火
Blame me. I can take the heat from Cam.
但你们得去克莱尔家住
You stay with Claire.
-因为我承受不住歌洛莉亚的怒火 -好
- 'Cause I can't take the heat from Gloria. - Right.
你一个字都别说 都交给我
Not a word. I do all the talking.
因为你很不会说谎
Because you're a terrible liar.
你来了 今天怎么样
Hey, there you are. Good day?
你这是什么意思
What...what's that supposed to mean?
你只有心虚的时候才会嗯哼
You only say that when you're guilty.
你身上有烟的味道
You smell like smoke.
天啊 你又把厨房烧毁了吗
Oh my god. Did you burn the kitchen down again?
就好像你根本不希望我帮你一样
It's like you don't want me to help you.